# 饺子大家谁都会包
Everyone knows how to wrap the dumplings
# 关键是调这馅儿
Yet not all know how to season the stuffing
# 上次做了一个三鲜馅饺子
We made Sanxian dumplings last time
# 很多网友又提出来了
A lot of you requested a video
# 能不能做个羊肉馅的
for making dumplings with lamb
# 饺子出锅啦 这大饺子
The dumplings are fresh out of the pot, looks delicious
# 这是一斤面 大约半斤水
This is one jin flour (0.5KG), About half jin water (0.25KG)
# 这个面 有的面吃水有的面不吃水
Some flour absorbs more water than others
# 说半斤水 但是最后还得灵活掌握
Even we said half jin water (0.25KG), we still need to be flexible about it
# 今天咱用的是中筋粉
We are using all-purpose flour today
# 防止饺子这面不得劲儿 搁点盐
Put in some salt in case the dough isn’t al dente enough
# 盐可以增加面粉的筋度
Salt can help to build the gluten of the flour
# 所以说为什么你不给他拿高筋
So why didn’t you give him the bread flour
# 他就拿盐代替一下
He uses salt as an alternative
# 这和面要想让它均匀
If you want to get an even dough
# 先把这面打成啰嗦
Knead the flour into strips first
# 您看您真是 一出手就知道是老手
Look at you, such a real professional
# 打成啰嗦我们逐渐的加点水
After we knead it into strips, gradually add some water
# 您打大疙瘩汤也好吃
The dough drop soup you made was really delicious
# 啰嗦就变大了
The strip is getting bigger
# 这时候我们可以往一块揣一揣
Then we can knead them together
# 还是那句话 三光
Again, “san guang” (bowl is clean, hands are clean, the dough is neat)
# 看看 半斤水 半斤水没了 正好
Look at it, half jin water (0.25KG), just the right amount
# 然后再揉揉
Then we keep kneading
# 原来饭店有时候包饺子
In the past, restaurants sometimes made dumplings
# 咱们到那也得学去
We would go there and learn it
# 你看这个面
Check out this dough
# 我们为了让它光 还要蘸点水
To make it neat, we need to add a little more water
# 做面食就得勤揉 把面揉润了
When we make food with flour, we need to knead it a lot to make it moist
# 行 找一个布一盖 找块小布
Done. Let’s find a cloth to cover it
# 得是湿的 饧着 给我
The cloth has to be wet. Let’s rest the dough. Give it to me.
# 洗洗手 现在第二步该是打馅
Wash my hands. Now the next step is to make the stuffing
# 全齐了我给你介绍介绍啊
It’s all here, let me introduce the ingredients
# 你看葱姜量都挺大
Lots of scallions and ginger
# 白菜 是隋坡一刀一刀切的 没剁
Napa cabbage (only the leaves). Sui Po cut it, didn’t chop it.
# 咱这要说明一下 白菜尽量别剁
We want to be clear, try not to chop the Napa cabbage
# 您看多整齐
How even it is!
# 花椒水 热水泡的花椒水
Sichuan pepper steeped water. Steeped with hot water
# 羊肉我们今天是事先给剁好了
We chopped the lamb ahead today
# 这是羊的后腿
This is the lamb hind leg
# 打这羊肉馅
Time to make the lamb stuffing
# 我们第一个要放花椒水
First, we put in the Sichuan pepper steeped water
# 羊肉是吃花椒的
lamb need to pair up with the Sichuan pepper
# 最好的配伍就是花椒 去膻
It is the best combination to get rid of the gamey smell
# 下盐
Add salt
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 来点老抽 看看颜色
Some dark soy sauce to give it some color
# 白胡椒粉 两克够了
White pepper powder, 2g is enough
# 这个我们开始用手打馅
We use our hands to beat the stuffing
# 手打馅打的匀 打的实在
The stuffing is more even and solid using the hand
# 朝一个方向打
Mix it with one direction
# 跟大爷似的 实实在在的
Just like Da Ye, solid
# 得摔上劲儿 就跟你摔丸子似的
You need to throw it to get the texture like you throw the meatballs
# 为什么我不习惯用筷子搅
Why I can’t get used to mixing the stuffing with chopsticks
# 有时候打的不匀 没劲儿
Sometimes it wasn’t mixed evenly and tender
# 在吃饺子里边 一般我们不加料酒
When we made the dumpling stuffing, we don’t normally use cooking wine
# 因为它煮的 那酒味出不出去
Because when it boils, the alcohol wouldn’t volatilize
# 所以不加
So we don’t add cooking wine
# 又加点老抽
Add more dark soy sauce
# 大爷的饺子最关键是什么
The key points of Da Ye’s dumpling
# 您看都能看明白了
You can see them clearly
# 调色 调味 调鲜 去膻
Coloring, Seasoning, Getting rid of the gamey taste
# 按道理如果说 羊肉大葱馅的
Normally, if we make the stuffing with lamb and leek
# 这个肉馅就有点硬
This texture would be too hard
# 我们就得加点花椒水
We need to add more Sichuan pepper steeped water
# 打上劲以后再加
Add the water after it has beaten enough
# 白菜馅我们就不加了
We won’t add more water to this stuffing with Napa cabbage
# 白菜也不用杀水 正合适
We don’t need to extract water from the Napa cabbage as well
# 大葱 姜 姜不要太多
Leek, not too much ginger
# 你看一抓 正合适
Grab it, the texture is just right
# 有时候看这盐看哪儿呢
Sometimes when we want to know if we need more salt
# 你看这白菜下去
You can see the cabbage is shrinking
# 待会它就塌下去了
It will sink later
# 说明这个盐就到位了
Which means we have enough salt
# 如果说半天这白菜还没下去
If the cabbage isn’t shrinking after a while
# 说明这咸味不够 这咸味差多了
Means it’s way not salty enough.
# 看着啊 拿手一抓
Look, I’m grabbing it with hands
# 这用羊肉做白菜馅儿的还真不多
It’s not common to use napa cabbage in lamb stuffing
# 大葱的多 但是搁点白菜
Mostly pairs up with leek, but add some napa cabbage
# 它煮出来以后白菜特别容易烂
After it boiled, the napa cabbage is really easy to become mushy
# 我得先闻闻这味
I’m going to smell it
# 还没搁香油呢
We haven’t added the sesame oil
# 等会儿搁上香油就香了
It’s going to smell really good after adding the sesame oil
# 香油
Sesame oil
# 这就是炸的料油
This is Liao You (the oil fried with many ingredients)
# 葱姜 适当再加点小茴香大料就行了
Scallions, ginger, and some fennel and star anise
# 肉馅儿特别肥就不用加油了
If the stuffing is very fat, there is no need for extra oil
# 少加 香油肯定是要加的
Don't add too much. Sesame oil is a must
# 油加完这馅儿特别润
The stuffing is moist after adding the oil
# 现在基本都是油打馅 好了
Now we all use oil in the stuffing. Done
# 二伯 面饧好了 看着啊
Er Bai, the dough is rested. Watch closely.
# 这回光滑了 开始包
It’s smooth now. Time to make the dumplings
# 看这羊肉馅还挺新鲜
The lamb stuffing is pretty fresh
# 这羊肉不错 不错吧 新鲜啊
This lamb is good. Right? It’s fresh.
# 煮饺子有一小窍门 搁点盐
Here is a tip for boiling the dumplings. Add some salt
# 这干嘛使呢 防止饺子出锅它粘
Why is that? In case the dumplings stick together out of the pot
# 防止它互相粘连 这就不粘了
In case they stick together. Now they won’t.
# 煮饺子得隆重 瞧着啊
Boiling dumplings need to be ceremonious. Look at it.
# 隋坡知道 因为所以 它不粘了
Sui Po knows. Because of the salt, they won’t stick.
# 往里面一推 理论家
Give them a little push. Theorists.
# 咱这锅大点多煮点
We can boil more with such a big pot
# 到时候粘成一锅了 不会的
What if they stick together. No, they won’t.
# 粘成一锅那就是片儿汤汆丸子
If they do, then it’s sliced dough soup with boiled meatballs.
# 煮饺子我们是这样
Here’s what we do when we boil the dumplings
# 顺着锅边 把这水给轰起来
Spin the water alongside the pot
# 旋转
Spin
# 开锅是煮馅 闭锅煮皮儿 为什么
Open-lid is to cook the stuffing, close-lid is to cook the dough wrap. Why
# 因为饺子在水里漂着 漂着的时候
Because when the dumplings flow in the water
# 它有上半拉皮是在水外边
Half of the wrap is flowing on the water
# 所以要盖上盖儿
So we need to close the lid
# 等皮儿就要快熟了
When the wrap is almost cooked
# 我们开始煮馅了 就得开着锅
We start to cook the stuffing with open-lid
# 如果再捂 就容易把饺子煮烂了
If we keep the lid close, the dumplings would break apart
# 皮儿就糟了
The wrap would be terrible
# 锅开了
The water is boiling
# 你看锅开大了 加点水
When you see the water boils, add some water
# 一是给它降降温
Firstly, it will cool done the temperature
# 二呢补充一点水分
Secondly, it will add more water
# 待会我们煮第二波
When we boil the second batch later
# 这水不会乱 不会黏糊
The water will not be messy and sticky
# 蒜泥 搁点醋 米醋
Minced garlic, add some vinegar, rice vinegar
# 在北京吃饺子一定要是吃米醋的
You have to dip rice vinegar when you eat dumplings in Beijing
# 少来点香油 香油多了它就不香
Add little sesame oil. Too much sesame oil will make it less tasty
# 这饺子煮到什么程度了你看
Let’s find out how’s the dumplings now
# 全鼓起来 鼓的跟小泡儿似的
All puff up, like small bubbles
# 起鼓不说了 还透亮呢
Not only puffs up but also lucency
# 摸摸 一按熟了
Give it a touch, it’s cooked
# 这个馅儿硬了 硬了就熟了
The stuffing is hard. Once it’s hardened, it’s cooked
# 好 捞了
Ok, scoop them out
# 来 照相
Time for photoes
# 这大饺子 饺子出锅啦
The dumplings are fresh out of the pot, looks delicious
# 肉馅你看都成团了
The suffering is shaped like a ball
# 有汤吗 有汤你看
Is there juice inside? Yes, look.
# 最关键是什么
What’s the most important is
# 肉非常鲜美 调味调的准确 还不柴
The meat is really tasty, the seasoning is perfect, and it’s not dry at all
# 这中筋面粉
The all purpose flour
# 师父放那一勺盐 起了作用了
The salt that the master added is working
# 要不然要裂  劲儿不够
Otherwise, the dough would break apart, the gluten would not be enough
# 它筋道了 韧性特别好
Once the gluten has developed, the strength becomes better
# 二伯看见没有 这饺子不粘
Er Bai look at it, the dumplings didn’t stick
# 你看要不然他不加点盐就全粘上了
They would be stick together without that salt
# 而且调味的这些香料
Add the ingredients for the seasoning
# 比如说花椒水 还有葱姜
Such as Sichuan pepper steeped water, and scallions and ginger
# 它没有把羊肉独有的香味去掉
They didn’t get remove the unique taste of the lamb
# 还保留了 特别好
It was well kept, really nice
# 有汁 很香
Juciy, tasty
# 馅儿挺嫩吧 嫩
Isn’t the stuffing tender? Tender.
# 还有您打那勺香料油
And the spoon of sesame oil you added to the stuffing
# 最后那勺恰到好处
That was perfect
# 要没这点油 这馅可能就有点干
Without that oil, the stuffing would be a little too dry
# 好 谢谢二伯 谢谢隋坡
Ok. Thank you, Er Bai. Thank you, Sui Po.
# 多吃点啊
Bon appetit!